A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Audiovisual materials FA750
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Ford Foundation Films, 1
  - Rural U.S.A. (Through Indian Eyes), 1952-1953 (Reel AV 1344A, Reel AV 1344B, Box 2, Dvd AV 1344A)
    Produced in 1952-1953 upon the occasion of a visit to the USA from a group of Indian dignitaries, focused on agriculture and farm technology. Includes the Department of Agriculture, the Tuskegee Institute, and various farms and communities throughout the south and southwest parts of the country. Narrated by M.S. Sundaram, produced by Charles Linko. Copyright retained by Ford Foundation. From Ford Foundation Grant 52-93.
  - Save the Children, 1974 (Reel AV 2014A, Reel AV 2014B, Reel AV 2014C, Reel AV 2014D, Reel AV 2014E, Reel AV 2014F, Reel AV 2014G)
    Conditions Governing Accessn note
    A documentary film that recorded the concert held in Chicago in 1972 as part of Jesse Jackson’s Operation PUSH exposition. Includes performances by Marvin Gaye, The Staple Singers, The Temptations, The Chi-Lites, The Main Ingredient, The O’Jays, Isaac Hayes, Zulema, The Cannonball Adderly Quintet, Albertina Walker, The Push Mass Choir, Loretta Oliver, Rev. James Cleveland, Bill Withers, Curtis Mayfield, Sammy Davis, Jr. Roberta Flack, Quincy Jones, Gladys Knight and the Pips, Jerry Butler, Brenda Lee Eager, Nancy Wilson, The Jackson 5 and Jackie Verdell. Also featured Rev. Jesse Jackson, Rev. Willie Barrow, Don Cornelius, Yvonne Daniels, Ossie Davis, Dick Gregory, Rev. Henry Hardy, Smokey Robinson, Richard Roundtree, Bill Rusell and Kim Weston. Directed by Stan Lathan and Narrated by Matt Robinson. Copyright 1974, Stellar Productions, Inc.
  - Scenes of Center for Advanced Study in Behavioral Sciences, Early 1950s (Reel AV 2196)
    Unedited footage from the early 1950s of various scenes at the Center for Advanced Study in Behavioral Sciences in Standford, California.
  - Scholarship Award Meeting, 1955 September 7 (Reel AV 1878)
    Meeting at the Palmer House.
  - See It Now: A Conversation with Dr. J. Robert Oppenheimer, 1955 January 4 (Reel AV 1893)
    An episode of Edward R. Murrow's"See It Now" broadcast featuring a discussion with Dr. J. Robert Oppenheimer, director of the Institute for Advanced Study. Murrow and Oppenheimer discuss the history of the Institute, its current fellows and projects, and its goals for the future in technology and science. Filmed 1955 January 4, this film is an extended version of the original aired broadcast (re-released for college and university use).
  - Shape (Reel AV 2002, Reel AV 1895, Reel AV 2001, Reel AV 1899)
    Seemingly stock footage of shapes found nature, architecture, human activity, and fine art: silhouettes of buildings and bridges, shadows of humans at play, natural forms like branches and flowers, and depictions of shape in paintings and sculptures. From Roemer, Young and Associates.
  - Simple Harmonic Motion, 1953 (Reel AV 1950)
    Short educational film produced in collaboration with the Visual Aids Committee of the American Association of Physics Teachers, from its basic physics series. Copyright 1953, McGraw-Hill Book Company.
  - Skies of the Andes (Reel AV 1982)
    Documentary on astronomy in Chile and the creation of the largest telescope on the South American continent. The telescope was funded by the Ford Foundation and the National Science Foundation for the Cerro Tololo Inter-American Observatory in Tololo, Chile.
  - Speed of Light (Reel AV 1986)
    An educational film on the velocity of light in air and water funded by the National Science Foundation, Alfred P. Sloan Foundation and Ford Foundation as part of its course in physics.
  - Stationary Longitudinal Waves, 1953 (Reel AV 1880)
    One episode from the Basic Physics series produced by McGraw-Hill Text Films, in collaboration with the Visual Aids Committee of the American Association of Physics Teachers. Copyright 1953, McGraw-Hill Book Company.
  - Stationary Transverse Waves, 1953 (Reel AV 1883)
  - Straight Line Kinematics, 1959 (Reel AV 1800)
    A short educational film about the study of motion, with Professor Everett M. Hefner of University of Rochester. Produced by Educational Services, Inc. Funded by the National Science Foundation, the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, and the Ford Foundation as part of a course on physics for secondary schools.
  - The Stranger (Reel AV 1841, Reel AV 2226, Reel AV 1842, Box 2, Dvd AV 1842)
    Dramatized story of government training program for young Indians to become agricultural specialists, working in rural India to improve traditional farming technologies. Written and produced by Lloyd E. Young. Presented by the Indian government with the assistance of the Ford Foundation.
  - Studies in Nigerian Dances (Reel AV 1844)
    Unedited footage of tribesmen performing native dances in villages in Nigeria
  - Studio Watts Tape: Addendum, 1970 (Reel AV 1980)
    Ford Foundation grant # 69-265 GRANTEE NARRATIVE REPORT OF 1970 March. Film contains four promotional commercials for Studio Watts, Los Angeles Learning Center for the Arts.
  - Technology in Public Service (Reel AV 2017, Reel AV 1958, Reel AV 2242)
    A Films Incorporated presentation about the development of new technology to improve living conditions in urban areas. A research and development unit called Public Technology Inc (PTI) partners with local governments and private investors to find and solve problems of transporation, high-occupancy housing, waste removal, etc. Presented by the Ford Foundation, in association with Nell Cox Films Inc. Produced and directed by Hilary Harris.
  - Technology in Public Service, Sound, 19 minutes. AV 2253A is an optical soundtrack, and AV 2253B is CRI (Reel AV 2253A, Reel AV 2253B)
  - Technology in Public Service, Sound and silent, black and white, 19 minutes. AV 2254A is an optical track, A 2254B is Orignial Negative, A Roll, CRI Amino Track, and AV 2254C is Original Negative, B Roll, CRI Amino Track. (Reel AV 2254A, Reel AV 2254B, Reel AV 2254C)
  - Television Teaching Demonstration: Fifth Grade Reading Lesson 27 (Reel AV 1984)
    Reading lesson for fifth grade students produced by WQED Pittsburgh Station. TV Teaching Demonstration was an experiment in using TV as part of daily basic instruction in the classroom.
  - Television Teaching Demonstration: Fifth Grade Reading Lesson 36 (Reel AV 1985)
  - That Our Children Will Not Die, 1978 (Reel AV 1968A, Reel AV 1968B, Reel AV 2209A, Reel AV 2209B, Reel AV 2217A, Reel AV 2217B, Reel AV 2230A, Reel AV 2230B)
    Soundtrack available separately, in multiple languages.
    An analysis of child health and living conditions in impoverished regions of Nigeria. Improved access to technology and well-train physicians are shown to be powerful tools, as well as localized programs and education to help villagers. With Professor O. Ransome-Kuti, director of the Institute of Child Health, University of Lagos, supported by the Ford Foundation. Produced, directed and edited by Joyce Chopra. Copyright 1978, Ford Foundation.
    Community health aides; Community health services; Public health; Nigeria; Nurse practitioners
  - That Our Children Will Not Die, 1978; Sound, Color, 60 minutes. Two copies available. Only available on 16mm. (Reel AV 2208A, Reel AV 2208B, Reel AV 2231A, Reel AV 2231B)
    ANALYSIS OF CHILD HEALTH AND LIVING CONDITIONS IN IMPOVERISHED REGIONS OF NIGERIA. IMPROVED ACCESS TO TECHNOLOGY AND WELL-TRAINED PHYSICIANS IS DISCUSSED, AS WELL AS LOCALIZED PROGRAMS AND EDUCATION TO HELP VILLAGERS. WITH BY PROF. O RANSOME-KUTI, DIRECTOR OF THE INSTITUTE OF CHILD HEALTH, UNIVERSITY OF LAGO, SUPPORTED BY THE FORD FOUNDATION. COPYRIGHT 1978, FORD FOUNDATION.
  - That Our Children Will Not Die, 1978; Sound, Color, 60 minutes. Two copies. Only available on 16mm. (Reel AV 2210A, Reel AV 2210B, Reel AV 2232A, Reel AV 2232B)
  - That Our Children Will Not Die, 1978; Silent and sound, color, 60 minutes. AV 2214A and AV 2216A are B Wind, and AV 2214B and AV 2216B are internegatives. (Reel AV 2214A, Reel AV 2214B, Reel AV 2216A, Reel AV 2216B)
    ANALYSIS OF CHILD HEALTH AND LIVING CONDITIONS IN IMPOVERISHED REGIONS OF NIGERIA. IMPROVED ACCESS TO TECHNOLOGY AND WELL-TRAINED PHYSICIANS IS DISCUSSED, AS WELL AS LOCALIZED PROGRAMS AND EDUCATION TO HELP VILLAGERS. WITH BY PROF. O RANSOME-KUTI, DIRECTOR OF THE INSTITUTE OF CHILD HEALTH, UNIVERSITY OF LAGO, SUPPORTED BY THE FORD FOUNDATION. COPYRIGHT 1978, FORD FOUNDATION
  - That Our Children Will Not Die, 1978; Silent, Color, 60 minutes. AV 2222A is B Roll original negative, and AV 2222B is A Roll original negative. (Reel AV 2222A, Reel AV 2222B)
  - That's Show Business (Reel AV 1427)
    In Spanish
    Soundtrack only to unknown film (possibly an episode of Continental Classroom.
  - They Call It Wildcat, 1974 (Reel AV 1799)
    Documentary about an employment program for recovering addicts and ex-convicts in New York City: a joint rehabilitation venture between local, state, and federal governments, utilizing methadone treatment, job training, Medicare benefits, and tutoring. The Wildcat Service Corp operated the Supported Work Program, developed by the Vera Institute of Justice, in cooperation with the NYC Department of Employment, the US Department of Labor, and others. Directed and produced by George C. Stoney. Presented by the Ford Foundation (copyright 1974). They Call It Wildcat is part of the film series Ford Foundation Films About Alternatives.
  - They Call It Wildcat, 1974; Sound, Color, 29 minutes. Only available on 16mm. (Reel AV 2199)
  - They Call It WildCat, 1974; Sound, Black & white and color, 31 minutes. Only available on 16mm. AV 2220A is a B Wind optical track, AV 2220B is B Roll, AV 2220C is A PIX. (Reel AV 2220A, Reel AV 2220B, Reel AV)
  - Tomorrow We'll See What Happens, 1973 (Reel AV 2198, Reel AV 1796, Reel AV 2206)
    Grantee film about three public schools in Los Angeles, CA who, facing issues of urban poverty, declining morale, and poor communication, adopted the Tutorial Community Project, a system of tutoring initiatives. Presented by Films Incorporated; copyright Ford Foundation, 1973.
  - Triumph of Technology: Flight from Land into Cities, 1956-1957 (Reel AV 2015 C, Reel AV 2015 B, Reel AV 2015 A)
    Scope and Content note
    Lecture 13 of a 15 part lecture series "A Changing World in the Light of Technology" presented by Arnold J. Toynbee at Washington and Lee University in Lexington, Virgina. Tonynbee details modernization, world migrations patterns, and rural to urban migrations. Copyright Encyclopedia Britannica Films, inc. 1958.
  - Turning Around:A Look At Neighborhood Housing Services, 1974 (Reel AV 1797, Reel AV 2186)
    A look at neighborhood housing services, modern trends in population movement, and the practice among banks and governments of abandoning poor neighborhoods, particularly in urban settings. Presented by the Ford Foundation in cooperation with the Urban Reinvestment Task Force of the Federal Home Loan Bank Board and the US Department of Housing and Urban Development. Produced and directed by Len Appelson. Copyright maintained by Ford Foundation.
  - Turning Around: A Look At Neighborhood Housing Services, 1974; Sound and silent, color, 22 minutes. AV 2218A is the Orignial Color Camera Negative A, AV 2218B is the Original Color Camera Negative B, and AV 2218C is the B Negative optical track. Only available on 16mm. (Reel AV 2218A, Reel AV 2218B, Reel AV 2218C)
  - Under One Roof (Reel AV 1777)
    A film by Frank Beaver about population management in the South: costs of child-raising, the development of birth control, and the importance of family planning. Presented by the Carolina Population Center.
  - Uniform Circular Motion, 1951 (Reel AV 1845)
    Film from the"Basic Physics Series" about uniform circular motion and velocity, to be used in the classroom. Produced by McGraw-Hill Text Films, in collaboration with the Visual Aids Committee of the American Association of Physics Teachers. Copyright 1951, McGraw-Hill Book Company.
  - Universal Gravitation (Reel AV 1983)
    An educational film on universal gravitation funded by the National Science Foundation, Alfred P. Sloan Foundation and Ford Foundation as part of its course in physics for secondary schools.
  - Vera and the Law, 1975 (Reel AV 1430)
    Film about the programs and activities of developed by the Vera Institute of Justice, "a private nonprofit corporation that works with police, courts, and social agencies to help make the justice system more efficient and fair". Produced by the Ford Foundation.
  - Village of Hope, 1956 (Reel AV 1795, Reel AV 2233, Box 2, Dvd AV 1795)
    Film produced by the Government of India, from their Community Projects administration. The program divides issues of poverty, sanitation, and education in rural villages as part of "old" (colonial) India, and new technologies and efforts to overcome these challenges as Young India. Funded by the Ford Foundation, copyright 1956.
  - The Walls Come Tumbling Down, 1975 (Reel AV 2205, Reel AV 2200, Reel AV 2187, Reel AV 2211, Reel AV 1345, Reel AV 2202)
    Film about the Housing Authority struggle in St. Louis in 1969 over tenement housing focused on the Pruitt-Igoe urban housing project. It examines the resident-management program in public housing projects in St. Louis. The film shows how the program has solved many of the problems of the residents and relieved the atmosphere of confrontation which plagued public housing in St. Louis before the introduction of the program. Copyright Ford Foundation, 1975.
    Series Statement
    Ford Foundation Films About Alternatives
    Public housing
  - Welcome to the Working Worlds! (Reel AV 2008)
    An introduction film to a 13 part series each exploring various occupational clusters including natural resources/environment, construction, manufacturing, transportation, marketing and distribution, business and personal services, agribusiness and food production, hospitality and recreation, health, education, fine arts and the social sciences, public service, business office, and communications and media.
  - We're Ni! He is a Mad Man (Reel AV 1981)
    A documentary for the Human Ecology Fund and directed by Raymond Prince, MD. Section of Transcultural Psychiatric Studies, McGill University. The film documents psychiatric disorders and Yerubic medicine in Yeruba, Nigeria. The documentary includes footage of diagnosis, treatment, care of patients, spiritual healing ceremonies, male and female cult practices, and comparisons of traditional Yerubic religion, Islam and Christianity?s relationship to psychiatric illness. Contains footage of animal sacrifice and female nudity.
  - What Happened in Seattle? The Origins of a School Desegregation Plan (Reel AV 1978)
    Ford Foundation funded documentary on community led voluntary action of school desegregation from 1978 through the early 1980s.
  - World Cultures (Reel AV 1853, Reel AV 2016B, Reel AV 2016A, Reel AV 2191B, Reel AV 2191A)
    Part of Ruth George Dobson's course in high school curriculum created for WQED Pittsurgh, Miss Dobson interviews Ford Foundation artist Ted Conut. They discuss his experience in Korea during the 1950s while working for the United Nations Film and TV Unit as well as royal court musicans, buddishism, technology, architecture, farming, poverty and family life.
- Ford Foundation Videotapes, 80 Item(s) 80 videotapes of various formats including 2" Quad, 3/4" Umatic, VHS and Digital Betacam.; Except where noted, the Ford Foundation videotapes are only available in their original format.
  RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Assistant Director, Head of Archival Services or RAC Assistant Director, Head of Digital Programs for details.
  The videotapes included in the collection are the products of various grants and internal initiatives, dating from mid 1970s to early 1990s.
  - [Untitled], 1/2" Open reel (Tape AV 10047)
  - 20 - Slides, 17 September 1982; 3/4" Umatic (Tape AV 10004)
  - 903, 3/4" Umatic (Tape AV 10005)
  - Across the River / A Community Dialogue with Hedrick Smith, 1 hour 56 minutes.; VHS (Tape AV 10006)
    PBS Version. Produced by Hedrick Smith productions.
    Separated from Ford Foundation records, Governance and Civil Society, Office Files of Michael Lipsky; Folder Hedrick Smith Productions, Inc. Separation Number: 2012.064.002
  - America's 1st School, VHS (Tape AV 10562)
    See also Ford Foundation grant 08550046 (PA855-46), WGBH Educational Foundation, PARTIAL SUPPORT FOR A FILM DOCUMENTARY UPDATING AND SUMMARIZING "THE PATTERSON PROJECT".
  - Appears blank, 17 September 1982; 3/4" Umatic (Tape AV 10003)
  - Aspira Consent Decree Panels - City University Graduate Center, 20 February 1976; 50 minutes.; 1/2" Open Reel (Reel AV 10007)
    See also Ford Foundation grant 07550657 (PA75-657), Aspira Association, Inc., SUPPORT FOR MONITORING BILINGUAL EDUCATION DEVELOPMENTS IN NEW YORK.
  - Blank tape, 3/4" Umatic (Tape AV 10008)
  - Classroom presentation - Lesson on DNA Molecule, 27 June 1962; 2" Quad (Reel AV 10002)
    Experimental production for Ford Foundation at Ryerson Institute. Teacher: Mr. Hutchington; Producer: D. McCarthy.
  - Community College of Baltimore - Ford Foundation Bridge Program, 1983-1984 (Tape AV 10009)
    See also Ford Foundation grant 08350862 (PA83-862), Community College of Baltimore, ASSIST URBAN COMMUNITY COLLEGE TO ENHANCE STUDENTS' OPPORTUNITIES TO TRANSFER TO FOUR YEAR INSTITUTIONS.
  - Conversations in Black - Frank Thomas with Charlene Hunter Gault, 29 January 1982; 3/4" Umatic (Tape AV 10010)
    Part of Converations in Blakc series. Unabridged Version.
  - Conversations in Black - Frank Thomas with Charlene Hunter Gault, 13 February 1982; 3/4" Umatic (Tape AV 10011)
    Part of Conversations in Black Series.
  - Conservation with Development - The Sukhomajri Experience, 23 October 1980; 17 minutes.; 3/4" Umatic (Tape AV 10012)
    India irrigation with Ford Foundation assistance (DAM PROJECT).
  - Conversations in Black - Frank Thomas with Charlene Hunter Gault, 16 March 1982; 3/4" Umatic (Tape AV 10021)
    Unabridged version.
  - Dance on a May Day, 2 December 1977 (Tape AV 10013)
    See also Ford Foundation grant 07850042 (PA785-42), National Dance Institute, GENERAL SUPPORT.
    Separated Materials
    Removed from Ford Foundation records, Education and Public Policy, Office of the Arts. Separation number 2011.078.011.
  - Dick Magat, 3/4" Umatic (Tape AV 10014)
    Interviewed by Denny Crimmins; Photographed by Richard Leacock in Super - 8; Edited and transferred by Janet Rifkin of Playback at M.I.T.
  - Edgewood College, 1/2" Open reel; 12 minutes (Tape AV 10015)
  - Feministas, 1981; VHS (Tape AV 10589)
    See also Ford Foundation grant 08151019 (PA81-1019) Corporacion Mujer Y Familia, DISSEMINATION OF RESULTS OF THE FIRST LATIN AMERICAN AND CARIBBEANFEMINIST ENCOUNTER HELD IN BOGOTA, COLOMBIA JULY 1981.
  - Flowers with Care, VHS; 9:43 minutes. (Tape AV 10561)
    See also Ford Foundation grant 08250411 (PA82-411), Flowers With Care, TO DEVELOP A FIRM BASE OF FINANCIAL SUPPORT IN ORDER TO EXPAND AND INSTITUTIONALIZE FLOWERS WITH CARE'S PROGRAM.
  - Focus on the Ford Foundation, 18 July 1982; 3/4" Umatic.; 31 minutes. (Tape AV 10018)
  - Focus on the Ford Foundation, Summer 1982; 3/4" Umatic; 60 minutes. (Tape AV 10019)
    Edited version: Composite of seven videotapes and slides).
  - Foundation for Art Education - Bryan Wolf - Screen Test, 3/4" Umatic (Tape AV 10020)
  - Fred Friendly, 15 January 1973; 3/4" Umatic; 30 minutes. (Tape AV 10022)
  - From the Editor's Desk, #13, 18 December 1981; 3/4" Umatic (Tape AV 10023)
    Franklin Thomas, President, The Ford Foundation; Dr. James Wall, Editor, The Christian Century; Orde Coombs, Contributing Editor, New York Magazine.
  - HANYA -- Portrait of a Dance Pioneer, 27 April 1984; 3/4" Umatic; 54:38 minutes. (Tape AV 10024)
    Documentary on the life & times of Hanya Holm. Executive Producer: Marilyn Cristofori, and Producer/Editor: Nancy Mason Hauser.
  - Innovations: Georgia's Alternatives to Prison, VHS; 28 minutes. (Tape AV 10560)
    Produced by Georgia Department of Corrections. The Alternative to Incarceration program of the Georgia Department of Corrections (GDC) is a systematic approach to planned offender management. It provides effective, productive alternatives to prison by means of a continuum of sentencing options incrementally arrayed with increasing degrees of punishment, control, supervision, and offender services.
    GDC's alternative sentencing program has become a model for others throughout the nation. The Georgia program has set the standard, clearly demonstrating that innovative sentencing can be an effective part of the criminal justice system. These options protect the public, punish the criminal, provide restitution to the victim and the community, and offer enormous savings to the tax payer.
    Funding for this film was provided by a grant from the Ford Foundation in recognition of the selection of the Georgia Department of Corrections as a winner of the Innovations in State and Local Government Award, a program of the Ford Foundation in collaboration with the John F. Kennedy School of Government at Harvard University.
  - Innovations in State and Local Government (Tape AV 10559)
    Harvard University
  - Interview with Ford Foundation, April 1976; 3/4" Umatic (Tape AV 10025)
    THe Research Foundation of State University of New York.
  - Learning Place, 11 August 1977; 3/4" Umatic; 60 minutes. (Tape AV 10030)
  - Learning Place, 11 August 1977; 3/4" Umatic; 60 minutes. (Tape AV 10031)
    School desegregation program.
  - Learning Place, 11 August 1977; 3/4" Umatic; 60 minutes. (Tape AV 10032)
  - Mama's Pushcart / Ellen Stewart and 25 Years of La Mama Experimental Theatre, 1 May 1987; 3/4" Umatics; 55 minutes. (Tape AV 10033)
    Ddirected by Demetria Royals
  - The Media and Human Rights, 2 May 1986; 3/4" Umatic; Audio mixed on both tracks.; 59:21 minutes. (Tape AV 10034)
    See also Ford Foundation grant 08550249 (PA85-249), Center for Communication, Inc, SUPPORT FOR ORGANIZATION, VIDEOTAPING AND DISSEMINATION OF SEMINARS IN THE "MEDIA AND HUMAN RIGHTS" SERIES.
  - Music Lessons, 2 April 1981; 40 minutes.; 2" Quad (Reel AV 10001)
  - Morris High School, 16 May 1983; 3/4" Umatic; 10 minutes. (Tape AV 10035)
    Segment on The Today Show. Includes Ed Meade briefly and hosted by Jane Pauley.
  - Off the Assembly Line, 23 May 1975; 60 minutes.; 3/4" Umatic (Tape AV 10036)
  - The Office Files of Gordon Berlin
    - Congressional Awards - Rostenchowski, 21 March 1985; 3/4" Umatic; 17 minutes. (Tape AV 10051)
    - Congressional Awards - Rostenchowski, 21 March 1985; 3/4" Umatic; 17 minutes. (Tape AV 10052)
    - Jobs for Connecticut's Future, VHS (Tape AV 10556)
    - Learning to Succeed, VHS (Tape AV 10558)
    - Make a Difference: Athletes for Youth Presentation Tape, VHS (Tape AV 10557)
    - Skilled Trades and Engineering: Explore the Possibilities, VHS (Tape AV 10563)
      Copyright, March, 1987.
    - The Moral Equivalent, VHS (Tape AV 10555)
    - The New Atari Color Learning Station, VHS (Tape AV 10568)
    - The Struggle to Save Rath Packing Part I, 3/4" Umatic; 44 minutes. (Tape AV 10054)
    - Tom Sticht - National Literacy Conference, VHS (Tape AV 10573)
    - Tom Sticht - National Literacy Conference (Tape AV 10574)
    - Tom Sticht - National Literacy Conference, VHS (Tape AV 10575)
    - Work Worth Doing Parts I & II, VHS; 60 minutes. (Tape AV 10579)
      The City of New York Department of Sanitation
    - Writing to Read, 20 July 1984; 3/4" Umatic; 13 minutes. (Tape AV 10053)
  - Open Mind, 17 March 1982; 3/4" Umatic; 60 minutes. (Tape AV 10037)